PORT OPERATIONS MANAGER

Executive Summary

Accomplished transportation/logistics manager with extensive experience in automobile transport operations, logistics, physical distribution and safety management. Experienced in DOT and OSHA requirements and CTPAT and FTZ certifications. Confirmed ability to lead and train large unionized trucking staffs and coordinate machinery and manpower for greater productivity and efficiencies.

Professional Experience
Bath Fitter January 2012 to July 2015 Port Operations Manager
Boston , MA

Coordinate and direct all logistic and production aspects of port operations, with a direct and indirect responsibility for 200 employees and
105 acres of processing facilities. Incorporated policies and procedures for the auto processor and auto transport companies to maintain and
resolve inventory, vehicle handling, quality and cost reduction issues for the efficient and effective management of 160,000 vehicles per year.
Monitor vendor and auto transport companies quality management systems during all phases of vehicle processing and transportation.

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Established excellent relationships with the Philadelphia Port Authority, Auto Transportation Companies, Teamster Local 107 and the Philadelphia PD
- Reduced carrier delivery times for the Northeast from 5 days to 2.8 days.
- Efficiently decreased vehicle processing time from 12 days to 8 days.
- Effectively negotiated land lease rates and contracts
- Increased daily production by 10% in 2015
- Formulated a new security plan that reduce security cost by 130K annually
- Instrumental in our facility receiving CTPAT and FTZ certification

ARROW TRUCK SALES INC. (a Volvo Company) April 2009 to December 2011 Sales Consultant City , STATE

- Accountable for growing the southern New Jersey pre-owned commercial truck market .Marketed class A and B vehicles to owner operators and corporate clients.
- KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS
- Consultant of the month six times in the first year
- Generated a data base of over 300 clients in less than two years.

MYCLOSINGSPACE, LLC September 2004 to September 2008 Closing Services Manager/Sales Program Manager City , STATE

 Ensured efficient real estate closings including processing, disbursement and customer service. Managed closing agent activities including scheduling, hiring and training. Implemented efficient work policies and procedures in order to provide superior customer service. Managed Quality Control of closed loan files to ensure government compliance. Coordinated and operated real estate and mortgage trade show events and assisted in developing company client base

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Produced a 98% customer service satisfaction rating through quality initiatives
- Negotiated and managed closing service cost with vendors resulting in an average annual savings of \$80K.
- Attained company goal of \$165.00 per closing

MAZDA NORTH AMERICAN OPERATIONS February 1993 to August 2004 Operations Manager (TWO SHIFT OPERATION) City, STATE

Directed and coordinated logistics activities, negotiated and implemented solutions to resolve inventory, vehicle handling, quality and cost
reduction issues involving 60,000 units per year. Managed Mazda's east coast export operation and negotiated with contractors to ensure
proper handling and cost effectiveness. Possess extensive knowledge of port operations pertaining to import, export, auto processing and
distribution and vast experience with the automobile assembly process and automobile transportation.

• KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Instrumental in achieving #1 ranking in J.D.Powers Initial Quality Study for B-Series (Product) in 1998 and 2002
- Built a solid relationships between Ford and Mazda personnel and management to better support product quality
- Reduced audited product defects by 50%
- Eliminated facility security and snow removal costs by successful negotiations with Ford and contractor resulting in savings of \$50,000 and \$30,000 respectively per year

- Negotiated reduction in contractor's rail loading and handling rate from \$75.00 per vehicle to \$37.50 resulting in savings of \$135,000 per vear
- Negotiated with Conrail to absorb vehicle inspection costs resulting in savings of \$600,000 over three-year period
- Decreased quality defects from 40% to 10% over ten-year period

LEASEWAY TRANSPORTATION AUTO CARRIER DIVISION January 1983 to January 1992 Damage Prevention Supervisor/Safety Superintendent City, STATE

- Supervised 100 union employees, worked with union representatives and managed grievance procedures and corrective action. Managed convoy and rail distribution process including load make up and dispatching. Managed 60 drivers at five pickup sites at Port Newark N.J. Trained new and current drivers in safety techniques, operations and new equipment. Including OSH and DOT requirements. Handled fleet safety inspection and supervised repair procedures. Analyzed and tracked damages and complaints in-order prevent future incidents.
- KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS
- Reduce accident and injury frequency by 60% and 74% respectively
- Reduced major cargo damage by 80%, damage exceptions by 55% and cost per unit by 80%
- Reduced carrier damage rate to less than 1%

Education

Middlesex County College Associate Degree: Applied Sciences (Marketing Physical Distribution City, State, USA

Applied Sciences (Marketing, Physical Distribution)

THE WILLIAM PATTERSON COLLEGE OF NEW JERSEY Select One: LIBERAL ARTS PROGRAM 30 CREDITS City, State, USA

Various programs including Highway Traffic Safety, Drug Awareness and Certificate of Achievement for Worker's Compensation Strategy.

Skills

Excel, Office XP, Outlook, Power Point, Windows 98, 98, Windows XP, Microsoft Word, SAP and VELES